Guide to the Juan Felipe Herrera Papers, ca. 1970-1998 M1043
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 9: Accession 2011-054
  - 34) 1 B/W of Anti US interention in El Salvador Rally. Dolores Park, SF. 1981 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - 35) 1 Color of Kayum Mario preparing the Cayuko. Lake Ocotal, Naja, Selva Lacandona, Chiapas, Mx. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - 36) 30 B/W of Mexico City. Negs only. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - 37) 36 B/W of San Cristobal de Las Casa, Mc. Negs only. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - 38) 6 B/W promotional shots of Abraham Adzenya (Ghana Master Drummer) and Monica Palacios (Performance artist). 1998? Negs only (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - 39) 10 B/W promotional shots of various artists. Michele Serros, Margarita Robles, Arlene Biala, Victor Hernandez Cruz, Ruben Martinez, Genny Lim, Abe Adzenya & JFH - for Summer Arts CSU program run by JFH. Late 90's. Negs only (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - 40) 3 images of JFH's Teatro Zapata. Late 90's. CSU-Fresno. (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - 41) 1 B/W copy of photo of Theatro Zapata. CSU-Fresno. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - 42) 12 Color of Yo Puedo Summer program students. UCSC. Santa Cruz. 1984. Anonymous (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 43) 39 B/W of Teatro Zapata. UC Berkeley. And CSU-Fresno. (directed by JFH). By Adan Avalos. 1997 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 44) 1 B/W of Dora Cordova (Mexico UNAM Anthro Student). Naja, Selva. Chiapas, Mx. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - 45) 7 B/W Contact sheet of Los Voladores at Tuxpam (Totonaca), Veracruz, August Festival. 1970. (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - 46) 1 Colorized image of wife, Margarita Robles and son, Robert Segura. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - 47) 1 B/W copy of "Plan del Mural colectivo elaborado en le celda de la Voz de Cerro Hueco". Chiapas. Zapatista Communique. November, 1999. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 48) 32 B/W of Teatro Zapata. CSU-Fresno(JFH director). Late 90's. By Tommy Monreal (from Huron, Ca.) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 49) 19 Color of JFH Chicano Studies Class - On Huichol Culture. CSUF. Late 90's. (with negs). Fresno (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 50) 1 Color of JFH on Frustas Street (Segundo Barrio), El Paso, Tx. 1984. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 51) 1 B/W of 11th TENAZ Theatro Festival. Point Bonita, Bay Area. (Members of Teatro de la Esperanza and Victor Martinez, Poet (with Glasses). 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 52) 1 B/W Contact sheet of JFH, Margarita Robles (wife) and Francisco Alarcon in Alarcon's Apartment. (JFH lived downstairs). San Jose Street & 25th SF. 1984. By Juan Pablo Gutierrez. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 53) 1 B/W promo shot - Margarita Robles, Feliz Alvarez (suit), Ricardo Talavera (Funky hat), JFH and Dominique Di Prima (Mission District). SF 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 54) 3 B/W of Dora Cordova, Nuk (Kayum Maax's wife) and other. Naja, Selva Lacandona. Chiapas, Mx. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 55) 2 B/W negs of Lim Romero, Poet [deceased 11/07] with Huichol children in Huichol Barrio shanty outside of Tepic, Nayarit and the other of morning after Huichol Sacred Corn Festival, Sierra Madre, El Colorin Rancho. Nayarit, 1970. Rare shots. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 56) 5 B/W negs of Lacandon youth preparing cayuko outside of Lake Naja, Naja, Selva, Chiapas. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 57) 5 B/W of Lacanja Chan Sayab. Selva Lacandona, Chiapas, Mx. 1970. By Tomas Mendoza Harell & JFH. Negs only. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 58) 5 B/W negs of Maruch and her family (Exiled Chamula, living in San Cristobal e las Casas, Chiapas). Mexico. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 59) 1 B/W promotional of Monica Palacios by Becky Villasenor. Los Angeles. 1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 60) 1 B/W of US of out El Salvador Rally at Dolores Park, SF. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 61) 1 Color of Manikrudo Ensemble performing JFH's Orientation Nation Cafe with Mark Izu on Bass (backdrop and Carmen Jimenez, poet, center). Arcata, Ca. CSU-Humboldt. Summer Arts. Anonymous. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 62) 3 B/W negs of rooftop scenes from Gran Hotel in North Veracruz, Mexico. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 63) 18 B/W negs of Huichol Ranchito, El Colorin, Sierra Madre, Nayarit, Mexico. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 64) 14 B/W negs of visit to Zinacantan, Chiapas. 1970 (musicians). (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 65) 1 Color of Mural scene by Victor Ochao (San Diego), 1985? (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 66) 1 Color of JFH on street Motorcycle. Montrose Street, Rialito, Ca. 1986. By Margarita Robles (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 67) 3 color of JFH's Chicano Studies class, CSU-Dresno. 2004 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 68) 1 B/W of Margarita Robles, Segundo Barrio, El Paso, Tx. 1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 69) 1 B/W of JFH and Francisco Alarcon, Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mx. 1978. Anonymous (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 70) 1 Color of Marvin Bell's poetry workshop (bottom right) at The Mill, Iowa City. JFH, Margarita (left), Matt Lippman (behind Margarita), Bruce Holbert (last on left). 1989. Anonymous. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 71) 1 Color JFH on pebble shore, Monterey, Ca. By Margarita Robles. 1996? (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 72) 2 Color of JFH giving a workshop to Bilingual Teachers at CSU-F. late 90's Fresno (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 73) 1 Color of JFH and friend poet, John Marron, Greenwhich Village, NYC. Anonymous. Mid 90's (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - 74) 1 B/W of JFH friend, Jorge Herrera-Belmont and his wife, Mariana and child. Mission District, SF. 1997 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 75) 1 B/W of JFH reading from Facegames at the Book Debut, Eulipia's, San Jose, Ca. 1987. Anonymous (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 76) 1 color of Margarita Robles, reading from her book Tryptich, at it's debut. SF. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 77) 36 B/W negs of Mexico City. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 78) 3 B/W negs of Nuk (Kayum Maax wife) and Dora Cordova. Naja, Selva, Chiapas. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 79) 9 B/W negs of Zinacantan, Chiapas. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 80) 10 Negs of Chan Kim Jose, Kayum Mario and Bor, youth in Naja, Selva, Chiapas, Mx. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 81) 63 B/W negs of Teatro Zapata, (JFH director). CSU-F. Mid 90's Fresno. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 82) 2 color of Cesar Chavez rally. Mid 90's. Dinuba, Ca. Anonymous (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 83) 1 Color of Matt Shenoda, Poet AWP Conference. 2002? Baltimore, Md. (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 84) 1 Color of JFH in Yo Puedo Classroom. UCSC. 1984 by Victor Carillo. (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - 85) 9 B/W negs of Manikrudo Workshop. CSU-Humboldt. Arcata, Ca. (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - 86) 3 B/W promo negs of Li-Young Lee, poet. Mid 90's. (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 87) 14 Color original slides of Naja Village, Selva Lacandona, Chiapas, Mx. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - 88) 24 B/W negs of San Cristobal de Las Casa, Chiapas, Mex. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - 89) 18 B/W negs of Tlatelolco Apartments and children. Mexico City. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - 90) 6 B/W negs of Kayum Mario, Naja Village, Selva, Chiapas, Mx. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - 91) 18 B/W negs of Mexico City. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - 92) 18 color slides of route from Naja to Ocosingo by bus. 1993. Chiapas, Mx. (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - 93) 3 color of Kayum Mario. Lake Ocotal, Selva Lacandona. Chiapas. Mx. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - 94) 120 B/W of San Cristobal de Las Casas. Chiapas. Negs and Contact sheets. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - 95) 36 B/W negs of Naja, Selva, Chiapas. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - 96) 12 Color negs of Indian Protest from Tzajalchen, in San Cristobal de las Casas, Chiapas. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - 97) 1 B/W of Margarita Robles, NYC. Mid. 90's (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - 98) 1 B/W of Lorna Dee Cervantes. At Eulipia's. San Jose, Ca. JFH Book Debut of Facegames. 1987. (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - 99) 4 Color of Margarita Robles, Ray Gonzales and Ruby Anaya at Chicago Arts & Humanities Festival.Late 90's. (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - 100) 1 Color of JFH and James Donlan (Mime artist) at CSU-F Summer Arts Gala. 2000. (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - 101) 1 Ticket to More Precious than Gold Art Sale at Juana Alicia's house. Foto with Emmanuel Montoya, Juanalicia, Margarita Robles and JFH. 1986 1986? (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - 102) 1 Color of JFH, Tom Lutz (Keyboards) and Geoff Becker (Guitar) at Univ. of Iowa Cultural Center. 1988 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - 103) 1 Color of JFH and rapper, Dominic Ricardo, Fresno, late 90's (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - 104) 1 Color of JFH setting up Teatro Zapata at Mesilla, NM. Border Book Festival, Late 90's (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - 105) 1 Color of JFH at Elipias, San Jose, Introducing Ishmael Reed and Victor Hernandez Cruz, San Jose, Ca. 1986 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - 106) 1 color of Margarita Robles receiving story Irvine award with Lucha Corpi and Maria Herrera Sobek in backdrop and Luis Leal on right. 1985. Irvine. (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - 107) 2 B/W promo shots of JFH. 2002. By Randy Vaughn-Dotta, CSU-F photog. (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - 108) 1 B/W promo shot of Dr. Loco (Jose Cuellar) signed to Tommy. mid 90's (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - 109) 1 B/W of Margarita Robles reading the poem ad JFH dreams on. Anonymous. SF, Juanalicia's art on display. 1985 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - 110) 1 B/W promo shot of JFH (back with mask), Dominique DiPrima (with radio), Felix Alvarez (with conga) and Margarita Robles (with frying pan) and Richard Talavera (laying down). Mission District, SF. 1986. Foto by Emmanuel Montoya (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - 111) 1 B/W promo shot of Margarita Robles. San Jose. Asian Pacific Performing Arts Series. San Jose, Ca. MAACLA Arts Center. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - 112) 1 B/W of Jose Antonio Burciaga. Last poetry reading with him. Sacramento, Ca. 3/28/96. By Mac Schwartz. Signed from Carmel, Ca. (Tony's beach residence). (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - 113) 3 B/W Teatro Zapata. CSUF. 2000? By Randy Vaughn-Dotta, CSUF Photog. (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - 114) 2 B/W of JFH and Denise Chavez, Novelist. At Chopes Restaurant. Mesilla, NM. By Russell Mott. 1/20/98 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - 115) 1 B/W of Eddy Robles (actor), Smiley Rojas (Actor) - life long friends and JFH. At MACLA arts center in San Jose, Ca. Benefit for Jose Antonio Burciaga. 1996. By Adan Avalos. (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - 116) 9 B/W of US out of El Salvador Rally at Dolores Park, SF. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - 117) 1 B/W of Jorge Gonzalez, poet. At Eulipia's. 1987 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - 118) 1 B/W Francisco Alarcon "Boxing at the Beach." SF. 1983. (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - 119) 1 Color Francisco Alarcon, Lucha Corpi and Cesar. A. Gonzalez. Palabra Nueva Prize. Irvine, Ca. 4/21/83 Anonymous (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - 120) 1 B/W JFH studio. 949 Capp Street #10 SF. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - 121) 1 B/W Francisco Alarcon interviewing TEC (Teatro Experimental de Cali). Tenaz Teatro Festival, 1981. Point Bonita, Bay Area. (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - 122) 1 B/W Charley Trujillo, Author. San Jose, Ca. 1985? (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - 123) 1 Color Margarita Robles Painting Her Nails. San Jose Street/25th Apartment SF. 1984 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - 124) 1 B/W Emilio and Francisco Alarcon. En route to Mexico City, Mexicali. 1979. (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - 125) 2 B/W Jose Antonio Burciaga. 11th TENAZ Teatro Festival. Mission Cultural Center, Mission Street. SF. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - 126) 1 B/W Hank Tavera. 11th TENAZ Teatro Festival. Mission Cultural Center. SF. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - 127) 1 B/W JFH at Eulipia's. San Jose, Ca. 1986 by Margarita Robles (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - 128) 3 B/W Film project for Ed Kissam. Jose Antonio Burciaga & Margarita Robles. 1985. San Jose, Ca. (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - 129) 1 B/W Karen Brodine. No Empire Mono Poem Festival. Project Artaud, SF. Ca. 1981 (co-organized with JFH - Poetasumanos Collective (Victor Martinez, Yvonne Yarboro Bejarano and Tina Alvarez Robles) (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - 130) 1 Color Chicano Moratorim LA, 1980. Whittier Blvd. (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - 131) 1 B/W Francisco Alarcon. North Beach Trattoria. SF. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - 132) 1 Color Elias Nandino. At the 150th Anniversary of his hometown, Cocula, Jalisco. By Francisco Alarcon. 9/82 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - 133) 2 B/W International Writers Conference. A) Francisco Alarcon with Ernesto Cardenal and b) Victor Hernandez Cruz with Ishmael Reed. Early 80's. Site? (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - 134) 1 Color Jorge Herrera, Poet. Mission District, SF. mid 80's. By Margarita Robles. (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - 135) 1 B/W Richard Talavera, Playwright, TENAZ, 11th Teatro Festival. Mission Cultural Center. SF, Ca. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - 136) 1 Victor Martinez, Poet and Novelist, SF, Beach. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - 137) 1 B/W Rodrigo Reyes. Performing vato loco, in The Leash. Mission Cultural Center, SF 1984 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - 138) 2 B/W TENAZ 11th Teatro Festival. Francisco Alarcon Interviewing TEC (Teatro Experimental de Cali, Point Boita Conference Room - Francisco Alarcon (right to left) Hank Tavera and Anita Quintanilla. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - 139) 1 Color of Francisco Alarcon's Living room. San Jose Ave/25th street, SF. 1984 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - 140) 1 B/W JFH and Tina Alvarez Robles. SF by Victor Martinez. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - 141) 1 Color Chicano park murals. San Diego, Logan Heights. 1984 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - 142) 1 B/W First Street Project Band. Francis Wong, Beau Cane, Wally Schnally and? San Jose, Ca. 1987 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - 143) 1 Color JFH ar Jose Antonio Burciaga's apartment at Stanford Univ. By Justo Alarcon. 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 144) 1 B/W JFH at Facegames Book debut. Eulipa's. San Jose, Ca. 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 145) 1 Color JFH & Lucha Corpi at Irvine Priza Awards, with Luis Leal. 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 146) 1 Color of "Funky Household & Blues Review" with JFH and Alex Di Prima. 1986. Eulipia's. San Jose. Ca. By Margarita Robles. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 147) 1 B/W "Military Control" by Harry Gamboa Jr. LA, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 148) 1 Color of JFH receiving FOCAL Children's Lit Award. LA Library. (Victor Carillo, with cap), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 149) 3 Color of JFH and Kent Harrui's Family. Carbondale, Ill. 1993 By Chaney Harruf. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 150) 1 Color Francisco Alarcon. Shopping for a camera SF. 1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 151) 1 Color Margarita Robles. Candlestick Park, Giants Game. SF. 1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 152) 1 Color JFH student's. Poetry Workshop. SIU. Carbondale, Ill. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 153) 35 Color and B/W of JFH Open Air Experiment. De Anza College. 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 154) 41 Color JFH Duplex and Carbondale, Ill scenes. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 155) 10 Color FOCAL award ceremony, with Friend, poet, Victor Carrillo. LA Main Library. 1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 156) 2 Color JFH, Margarita Robles and friend, Anita Idrogo, in North Beach. 1999 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 157) 64 color JFH's Grad Poetry Workshop - Experimental approaches - SIU, Carbondale, Ill. 9/92 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 158) 27 Color Yo Puedo Program at UCSC. JFH's class. 1985 Santa Cruz, Ca. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Various Photographs (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 159) 3 Color Chicano Moratorium March from San Jose, Ca. to LA. And Moratorium shots. 1980. Anonymous (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 160) 1 B/W Cesar Chavez UFWU Conference. Coachella. 1974 Anonymous. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 161) 1 B/W MediaMix Program - More Precious than Gold. Art Auction and Poetry reading with Juanalicia, Emmanuel Montoya, Margarita Robles & JFHerrera. SF, Ca. 1986 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 162) Misc: Miquitzli - A Journal of Arte, Poesia, Cuento y Canto. Spring Qtr. 1978. Stanford University. Stanford (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 163) 1 MediaMix Presents Flyer. 1986. San Jose. "Funky Household" Latino Comedy. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 164) The American Poetry Review. Vol. 20/No. 1. 1991. JFH back cover feature. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 165) Arts & Books Section of the San Jose Mercury News. San Jose, Ca. 8/19/90 - Feature of Felix Alvarez (early member of Teatro Campesino). And Chicano/Latino Teatro. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 166) Various Promo Head shots in B/W of various writer/friends (Victor Hernandez Cruz, Li-Young Lee, Ruben Martinez, Michele Serros, Monica Palacios and Ghana Drummer Abraham Adzenya. Mid-90's. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 167) Art work by Lidia Rojas and Anonymous print from Mexican Artist. Late 90's. Fresno, Ca. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 168) Two Articles on Victor Martinez winning Natioal Book Award. SF Examiner (11/10/96) and Fresno Bee (11/9/96). (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 169) Issue of Tonantzin - V. 6. No. 3. Special Chicano Lit Issue. (JFH and many orthers) 10/1990. Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center. San Antonio, Tx. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 170) 5 Issues of El Tecolote Literario. (Supplement of El Tecolote). SF. 1982-1985. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 171) Receipt: Lay Away Purchase of Statue of Jesus. Redlands. 2009. (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 172) Letter from Cecilia Brunazzi, graphic designer for Exiles, Akrilica and Facegames. This letter is regarding Akrilica. SF. Late 80's. (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 173) Original Ms. of poems from Joshua Ryan, son of JFH, with Post Card. Late 90's Fresno, Ca. (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 174) Various Cartoons - "Hispa-Trendz" by JFH. Mid-90's Fresno, Ca. (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - 175) Chapbook of Josh Ryan's Ms. Removable Souls. (JFH's son). Sykic-Groove Press. 1996. (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 176) Chapbook of Josh Ryan's Ms. Removable Souls. (JFH's son). Sykic-Groove Press. SF. 1996. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 177) 2 Love letters from Margarita Robles. SF. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 178) Post card from Joaquin Herrera (JFH son). 1989. Iowa City, IA. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 179) Ms. Draft of Nakkaloo, The Girl Who Lived in a Hip-Hop Shoe. For Kindergard Project by Small Press Trafic inc. In Sf. For Theatre in 2010. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 180) Letter from Az. University Press regarding Blurb for Dixie Salazaar's New Book. 8/6/09 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 181) Early Draft of YA Poetry Book. Los Scraper Bike Boyz. 9/09 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 182) Letter from friend, Anita Leal Idrogo. Regarding new Publication. 9/7/98 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 183) Xmas Card from Film & TV Producers: Greg Nava and Barbara Martinez Jitner. 2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 184) 1 Color Copy of "Heart Rate?" Ramiro Martinez, artist. Fresno, Ca. late 90's (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 185) 2 Brief Reviews of Half of the World in Light - New and Selected Poems. Clips sent by Univ. of Arizona Press. 9/8/09 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 186) Copy of poem by Marisela Norte, "Vestida y Alborotada." Los Angeles, Ca. Mid-80's. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 187) Folder of some of the art and cards from participating artists in Latino Comedy Book, "Cilantro Facials." (Gary Soto, Gloria Velazquez, Paul Espinoza, Francisco, Alarcon, Norma Alarcon, Dwayne Big Eagle, Victor Carrillo, Arlene Biala, Liz Bahn, Roberto Alvarez, Rita Magadaleno, John Marron, Juana Alicia, Alejandro Murguia, Pat Payne, Denise Chavez, and more. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 188) Letter from Cousin, Vicente Quintana - from Soledad Correctional Facility. After meeting on a Saturday while teaching poetry workshop to inmates. 12/86. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 189) Typewritten poem by Martin Espada, "Grito for Nicaragua" Signed. Early 80's? (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 190) Issue of Red Trapeze, 1981. Featuring Thom Lee. SF, Ca. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 191) Invitation to Lawrence Ferlinghetti's "Drawing from Life." SF. 9/10/09 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 192) JFH Poetry reading Program for Univ. Az. Press. 4/23/02? (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 193) Letter from Greg Nava and Barbara Martinez Jitner requesting permission to use poetry in forthcoming TV Series of American Family PBS. 10/16/06. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 194) Invitation to apply to position at Univ. of Minnesota. 10/03 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 195) Letter from Ms. Concha Rivera (Tomas Rivera's widow) regarding Tomas Rivera Annual Conference work done. 5/13/05 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 196) 2 Letters: From Heyday Books regarding intro to Tim Hernandez's first first book of poetry (2/9/04) and Mathere Haines regarding use of poem for musical composition. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - 197) Coralito's Bay children's book release celebration papers. Monterey, Ca. 6/20/04 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 198) Sing or Speak - Benefit for Calif Poets in the Schools. SF. 10/24/04 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - 199) Check made to JFH from Curbstone Press for royalties on Love After the Riots. $11.41 with account paper. 9/9/09 (perhaps only royalty check received since 1993) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - 200) Two 2009 artist programs for MACLA latino arts center. San Jose, Ca. 2009 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - 201Two poems from Mayra and Alfonso Guillen Reyes, teen poets from Tucson, Az. Who survived crossing the Arizona Deser from Mexico. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - 202) Program from 8th Annual Northern Arizona Book Festival. 4/15/05 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - 203) Book Cover Draft Design: Border Crosser with a Lamborghini Dream. Univ. Az. Press. Late 90's. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - 204) MACLA 1999 Floricanto Festival & Conference Program. San Jose, Ca. 1999 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 205) Various dust jackets for Cinnamon Girl (Harper Collins - Joanna Cotler Books) and Downtown Boy. (Scholastic) NYC. 2004-5. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - 206) Various poetry drafts b JFH - "Violet Spiritual" "Ya esta la cosa." Handwritten and Typed. 2008-2009 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - 207) Draft of Ethnographic Novel by Robert Alvarez (anthropologist). Fronterizo: A Border Odyssey. 2004. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 208) Ms. Suburbs and Canticles by Ramon Garcia. 2004? Fresno area writer. (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - 209) Ms. Somewhere Else. By Mathew Shenoda. 2004. (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - 210) Production Staff Contact Sheet for The Upside Down Boy Musical for Young Audiences. NYC. 2004 (based on JFH book). (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - 211) Ms. No Man's Land by Eduardo Antonio Parra. City Lights. SF. for blurb. 2/20/07 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - 212) Ms. Poetry Sample: Thunder Lovers and Primary Clors. Brenda Cardenas. 2007? (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 213) Ms. Adobe Odes by Pat Mora. Request for Ms. Evaluation. Univ. Az. Press. 6/1/05. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 214) Book Outline: from Annice Jacoby. 10/1/03 (with color samples). SF. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Box Listing (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1) Ms. Welcome to Salsaland. By JFH (Hyperion). Artist draft (Susan Guevara). Hwr, was dumped due to budget. 6/21/03 with artist letter. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 2) Program: Hispanic Female Conference. 7th Annual. CSU-Fresno. 1/9/04. Founded by Margarita Robles. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 3) Two 1st draft ms. "No se como te voy a cantar.." and "Cruce la frontera, amor.." by JFH. Unpub. With draft of Guggenheim Fellowship app. Letter. Handwritten. 9/5/09 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 4) Ms. Draft. Of Nakkaloo, the girl who lived in a Hip-Hop Shoe. 6/27/09 - for theatre project. SF. 6/27/09 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 5) First draft of "Los vampiro de la calle whiter" for poetry book (by same name) in translation to be published by Sur+ ediciones. In Mexico, City. 2009. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 6) First draft of Book TOC Outline of "Los Vampiros de Whittier Blvd." 9/09 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 7) Various letters to JFH and Margarita Robles from various cultural arts enterprises. 2000-1. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 8) Flyer for Emergency Reading in Memory of Roque Dalton. 5/24/1987. 20 Named poets. SF. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 9) Folded and gathered sheets for Laughing Out Loud I Fly. Harper Collins - Joanna Cotler Books. 1998. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 10) Program (directed by JFH): Writer's Week - UCR. 2/07. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 11) No Vale Nada La Vida - Border Death Conference. 2008. Tucson, Az. (JFH reading). (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 12) La Mano Pachona. Oral History Project. CSU-F. (directed by JFH). 2001 (Box 8, Folders 16-20)
  - 13) JFH Promotion File. CSU-F. 1998-99. (Box 9, Folders 13)
  - 13) JFH Promotion File. CSU-F. 1998-99. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 14) JFH favorite writing exercise sheets. (original). (Box 10, Folders 2-3)
  - 16) Appreciation Album from Galveston Elementary School. Chandler, Az. (fotos, lettera, drawings) 9/07. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Box Listing (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - I live in a Hut (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Prima Road Notebook (Box 10, Folder 7)